

RORAIMA CHÁVEZ

Data Analyst

rorichavez97@gmail.com | +34 653599379 | Barcelona, Spain Linkedin | Github

ABOUT ME

Data analyst with experience in data management and visualization, as well as extensive knowledge of Python, SQL and Tableau.

I have strong communication, collaboration and presentation skills. I enjoy solving problems and paying attention to the small details, skills that I have developed thanks to my past as a producer, where I participated in the organization of events such as the launch of the Chinese car brand OMODA.

I want to succeed in a stimulating and challenging environment, where I can help build the company's success and can implement my critical thinking and have the opportunity to continually expand my knowledge in the field.

SKILLS

Python, SQL, Tableau, Power BI, Pandas, Seaborn, Machine Learning, Excel, Git, Polars(Basic), Snowflake (Basic).

Problem Solved - Strategic thinking - Effective communication - Project management

Languages: Spanish - Native, English - Advance, Catalan - Intermediate

EDUCATION

IronHack - Data Analytics Intensive Bootcamp

April 2024 - June 2024

Intensive bootcamp in data analytics, with learning by doing methodology. I did more than 5 projects and acquired a solid knowledge of fundamental skills such as:

- Python, MySQL, Tableau, Github.
- Artificial Intelligence and big language models such as ChatGPT, among other things.

Ramón Llull University - Audiovisual Communication

September 2015 - June 2019

Degree where I developed skills as a producer and event creator. I educated myself on professional tools in the industry, such as Final Cut, Premiere, Photoshop, InDesign, the Adobe suite and the Mac suite.

Instituto Marketing - Community Manager

May 2023 - June 2023

- I learned techniques to manage brand image, effective strategies in content creation and social media management.
- Developed skills in the creation of Social Media Marketing plans and data analysis to optimize results in networks such as LinkedIn and Meta apps.

PROJECTS

<u>Dating app</u> - A demographic analysis of the users on the dating app revealed key insights for finding potential partners. Additionally, using data obtained through web scraping, I developed an application to filter and identify compatible matches within the app.

<u>The Film Industry</u> - During this week-long project, I conducted a thorough analysis of the audiovisual industry, using a variety of languages and tools such as Python, Seaborn, Pandas, web scraping, APIs, Kaggle, and performed basic data cleansing tasks to ensure data quality.

A/B Testing - Using pre-determined KPIs, I had to analyze the results of the latest digital experiment conducted by the UX/UI team for the company Vanguard.

EXPERIENCES

Actimundi

Producer

January 2024 - April 2024

- I organized more than 5 events and stands for national and international fairs.
- I was in constant communication with more than 8 vendors and clients at the same time to coordinate events.
- I prepared budgets using Excel and managing teams using tools such as Trello.

Garage Films - Infinito Studios - Fake Studios

Production assistant & Office Manager

September 2015 - December 2023

- Worked closely with the administration department to close projects through the use of Excel.
- I developed multitasking skills and a great ability to adapt to meet the needs of any department.
- I organized teams, managed suppliers and actively collaborated on set.

DR Digital Agency

PR&Comms Account Manager

- Presenting key performance indicators (KPIs).
- Calendar management and content writing on social networks using the Hootsuite tool.
- Writing and distributing press releases, creating and publishing blogs, contacting journalists, etc.

April 2021 - August 2021